fivefilters.org 2019-11-02

# Privacy Policy | fivefilters.org

This privacy policy sets out how FiveFilters.org uses and protects any information that you give FiveFilters.org when you use this website or the applications hosted here.

FiveFilters.org is committed to ensuring that your privacy is protected. Should we ask you to provide certain information by which you can be identified when using this website, then you can be assured that it will only be used in accordance with this privacy statement.

FiveFilters.org may change this policy from time to time by updating this page. You should check this page from time to time to ensure that you are happy with any changes. This policy is effective from 20 August 2011.

### Information we may ask for

We try to collect as little information as possible. Most of what we ask for is the minimum we need to provide the services we do, and most of the information that is supplied is discarded as soon as it has served its purpose. Depending on the services you use on FiveFilters.org, we may ask for the following information:

  * URLs of web pages or feeds (stored temporarily on our servers to improve performance)
  * Your Kindle email address and, optionally, an email address on your approved Amazon Kindle list (used for sending articles, but not stored on our servers after sending completes)
  * Your API key if you register as a paying customer
  * Your email address if you register as a paying customer or join our forums

Occasionally we also enable logging on our servers for statistical analysis. When logging is enabled, IP addresses are stored. We destroy logs once they have served their purpose.

### What we do with the information we gather

The information we collect is used to ensure optimal system performance and to improve the services we offer. We do not share this information except when necessary to carry out the requested task - for example, to deliver web articles to your Kindle using your Kindle email address, we have to communicate and share information with Amazon's servers.

If logging is enabled, the information collected (such as IP addresses) is never shared with anyone else.

### Security

We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorised access or disclosure, we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.

### Cookies

None of our services currently rely on cookies, but we do use cookies for paying customers to improve the experience of some of our services.

A cookie in no way gives us access to your computer or any information about you, other than the data you choose to share with us.

You can choose to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. You can still take full advantage of the website with cookies disabled.

### Links to other websites

Our website may contain links to other websites of interest. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy statement. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.

### Controlling your personal information

If you believe that any information we are holding on you is incorrect or incomplete, please write to or email us as soon as possible at fivefilters (at) fivefilters.org. We will promptly correct any information found to be incorrect.
